'71 is a thriller, action, drama film directed by Yann Demange.
A young British soldier must find his way back to safety after his unit
accidentally abandons him during a riot in the streets of Belfast.
Gary Hook, played by Jack O'Connell.
Captain Sandy Browning, played by Sean Harris.
Sergeant Leslie Lewis, played by Paul Anderson.
Lt. Armitage, played by Sam Reid.
C.O., played by Sam Hazeldine.
Sean Bannon, played by Barry Keoghan.
'71 is a 2014 British thriller film directed by Yann Demange (in his
feature directorial debut) and written by Gregory Burke.
Set in Northern Ireland, it stars Jack O'Connell, Sean Harris, David Wilmot, Richard Dormer, Barry Keoghan, Paul Anderson and Charlie Murphy, and tells the
fictional story of a British soldier who becomes separated from his unit during a riot in Belfast at the height of the Troubles in 1971.
Filming began on location in Blackburn, Lancashire, in April 2013
and continued in Sheffield, Leeds and Liverpool.
The film was funded by the British Film Institute, Film4, Creative Scotland and Screen Yorkshire, and had its premiere in the competition section of the 64th
Berlin International Film Festival, held in February 2014, where it was particularly praised for O'Connell's performance and Demange's direction.
The film explores themes of 1970s, riot, northern ireland, survival, soldier.
The tone is emotional and intense.